Guide to the Rosa M. Eyer Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Rosa M. Eyer papers
1940-1972
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
6178
6178-001
Eyer, Rosa M.,$d1910-1997
0.42 cubic feet 1 box
Papers of Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers officer Rosa M. Eyer related to her work and personal life.
Rosa Millo Eyer (1910-1991) was Recording Secretary of the Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers (AWPPW) Local 644 in Everett, Washington in 1965 and AWPPW Secretary-Treasurer of the Northern Washington and Alaska Area Council during the 1960s and 1970s. She gave birth to three daughters: Gerry, Josephine, and Caroline with first husband Richard J. Millo. She later married Pacific Northwest paper worker representative John H. Eyer around the mid to late 1960s. Rosa retired from the union in 1972. She passed away in Everett, Washington at the age of 81 on November 10, 1991.
The collection is arranged into the following series:
SERIES 1: ASSOCIATION OF WESTERN PULP AND PAPER WORKER RECORDS
SERIES 2: PERSONAL PAPERS
The papers of Rosa Millo Eyer consists of a small series of Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers (AWPPW) records and another of personal papers. The first series is primarily AWPPW Northern Washington-Alaska Area Council records of which Rosa was Secretary-Treasurer, including correspondence, news clippings, notes, and Executive Board reports from Area Representative John R. Swanson as well as a file of correspondence related to Rosa's employment with the union. The series of personal papers consists primarily of letters to and from Rosa and her daughters, Gerry, Josephine, and Caroline; divorce and death records and ephemera from her first marriage with Richard J. Millo; several photographs of family members; and other correspondence to and from Rosa.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
No restrictions on access.
Donated by Rosa Millo Eyer, originally a part of the John H. Eyer papers (3932-001).
Due to the collection's distinctiveness as a body of records created or acquired during the course of Rosa M. Eyer's work and personal life and the importance of bringing out women's contributions to the labor movement whenever possible, this collection was separated from the
John H. Eyer papers (Manuscript Accession 3932-001)
during processing in January 2017.
Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers records (manuscript collection 2052)
Eyer, Rosa M.,$d1910-1991$vArchives; Labor unions$zWashington (State); Labor$zWashington (State); Labor movement$zWashington (State); Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers; Women labor union members$zWashington (State); Records (Documents); Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Labor History; Women
- ASSOCIATION OF WESTERN PULP AND PAPER WORKER RECORDS, 1965-1972; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 1/1-3)
  - Northern Washington-Alaska Area Council Records, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 1/1-2)
  - Rosa M. Eyer's Employment with the Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers: Correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 1/3)
- PERSONAL PAPERS, 1940-1972; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 1/4-10)
  - Invitation to Rosa's Retirement Party, 1972 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Letters to Rosa from Daughter Gerry, approximately 1970-1972 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Josephine M. Millo: Correspondence and Ephemera, 1963-1980 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - James Adams: Death Certificate and Funeral Ephemera, 1955 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Letters to Family from Daughter Caroline, 1955, 1972 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Class of 55: Photographic Portrait of Caroline, 1955
  - Richard J. Millo: Divorce and Death Records, approximately 1940-1955, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Unidentified Group Photograph of People Sitting Around Banquet Table, approximately 1940-1950
  - Assorted Correspondence to and from Rosa, 1960-1972 (Box-folder 1/10)